## **MIT** JOSHI

+91 78599 26143



mit\_joshi@outlook.com



www.linkedin.com/mit-joshi



# Software Developer <a href="https://react-js-portfolio-2024-mit-joshi.vercel.app/">https://react-js-portfolio-2024-mit-joshi.vercel.app/</a>

### **SUMMARY**

Highly motivated and professional Front End and WordPress Developer with over 3.5+ years of experience in coding and web development. Holds an MBA and possesses exceptional communication and interpersonal skills. Proven ability to work independently and collaboratively, with over 2+ years of experience as a Customer Service Manager.

#### SKILLS

- React JS, Tailwind CSS, HTML DOM, JavaScript
- REST native, Jest, Webpack, Redux, Wordpress, html, css
- Git & Github, JSON
- · Vercel, Netlify, Zoho connect, Jira
- npm, yarn, vite
- Performance Optimization: Lazy loading, Code splitting, Minification and bundling
- Blender, Procreate, Photoshop
- Exceptional communication and interpersonal skills
- Ability to work independently and as part of a team

## **CERTI & PROJECTS**

- Created React Job Portal web app.
- Many websites in React JS.
- One mobile app in React Native.
- You can check my projects on my github.
- Many certifications from online resources like edx, coursera, udemy, etc..

## **EDUCATION**

## Richmond, The American International University in London

Master's Degree in Business Administration 2019 – 2021

Bachelor's in Science PCM

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Senior Frontend Developer**

Stersoft Solutions Pvt Ltd | Jul 2024 - Oct 2024 | Vadodara | Full-time, On-site.

- Led the redesign of 40+ modules and the company's ERP system, improving user experience and interface consistency.
- Optimized the performance of TheERPHub (https://theerphub.com/), increasing the site health score from 83% to 95%.
- Supervised and mentored a team of junior developers, ensuring adherence to best practices and successful project delivery.
- Developed and maintained WordPress websites for various clients, including:
  - Tvarit (https://tvarit.com/)
  - Future Sales (https://www.futuresales.com/)
  - CT Designs (https://ctdesigns.in/)
  - Ishan Equipments (https://www.ishanequipments.com/)
  - And other high-quality projects.
- Consistently delivered solutions aligning with client requirements, enhancing both functionality and aesthetic appeal.
- This role showcased my expertise in front-end technologies, leadership abilities, and commitment to improving web performance and user satisfaction.

#### Software Developer

Ocean Technolab | Jan 2022 - Present | Vadodara | Full-time, Remote.

- Below Websites are Developed and maintained by me, showcasing expertise in front-end and WordPress development.
- Ossoues Orthopedic Implants & Instruments Manufacturer
- Website: https://osseous.in/
- Taksh Infinity A website dedicated to Marvel and DC action figure collections.
- Website: https://takshinfinity.com/

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Mighty Thread An apparel store built on the Shopify platform, offering a wide range of clothing options.
- Website: https://mightythread.com/
- Small World Immigration A website providing immigration services with detailed information and resources for individuals
- seeking to immigrate.
- Website: https://smallworldimmigration.ca/
- Hasten Sourcing A website representing a sourcing company, showcasing its services and capabilities in the sourcing industry.
- Website: https://hastensourcing.com/
- · Probal A website for a compliance and CA firm, offering services related to compliance and financial advisory.
- Website: https://probal.in/
- Lucianne Boutique An apparel store offering a curated selection of clothing items and accessories.
- Website: https://lucianneboutique.com/
- Empire Custom Homes A website providing information about custom home building services, showcasing past projects and testimonials.
- Website: https://empirecustomhomes.ca/
- Curis Lifesciences Pvt. Ltd. Pharmaceutical Company
- Website: https://curisls.com/
- Toastmasters International District 98
- Website: https://district98.org/

#### **Customer Service Manager**

IFON-TOUCH UK LTD | Sep 2019 - Dec 2021 | London, England, United Kingdom | Part-time, On-site.

- Help customers to send their money via Western Union & Ria money transfer service.
- Developed open and professional relationships with team members, enabling better, more effective customer service.
- Increased employee productivity by establishing and monitoring customer care performance indicators, service level metrics and goal achievement.
- Drove quality customer experiences by leading retention strategy development and conflict resolution to improve overall support delivery.
- Communicated sales targets and worked with front-line supervisors to enhance revenue numbers and promotional techniques.

#### Front End Developer

DOT2DOT InfoSoft Technologies Pvt. Ltd. | Jan 2018 - Dec 2018 | Vadodara | Full-time, On-site.

- Prepared branding packages for point of purchase displays, marketing materials and product packages.
- Formatted print and web applications designs and media to deliver production-ready graphics.
- Submitted design ideas to plan projects with customers and managers.
- Collaborated with writers and producers to translate visions into visuals.
- Created successful websites that met requirements for objectives such as load speed and design.
- Developed sites to work with Microsoft Edge, Mozilla Firefox and Google Chrome.
- Worked with product designers and product managers to design user interactions in applications.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Senior Graphic Designer, 2d Animator

Cerebroz EduTree | Jan 2017 - Dec 2017 | Vadodara | Full-time, On-site.

- · Participated in client meetings to discuss project scope, expectations and completion dates.
- Developed engaging marketing and promotional advertisements to generate sales revenue and grow customer base.
- Collaborated with writers and producers to translate visions into visuals.
- Used After Effects, Photoshop & Illustrator to create realistic characters with full range of emotions and movement.
- Oversaw work of junior designers, keeping team members working within established deadlines.
- Maintained archive of projects following established file standards.
- Designed mock-ups and wireframes utilizing graphics software skills.
- Enhanced design process by offering multiple solutions in conceptual models, layout and typography.

#### **Faculty of Hardware & Network**

IANT (Institute of Advance Network Technology) | Jan 2016 - Dec 2016 | Vadodara | Part-time, On-site.

• During my graduation, I was learning hardware and Networking and the Institute felt that my performance was extra ordinary so they gave me part time job of faculty.